Guide to the Chester Loomis papers, 1813-1865.
Loomis, Chester papers, 1813-1865.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
1813-1865.
2238
Chester, Loomis 1789-1873.
3.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, legal documents, financial records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include correspondence, deeds and agreements, personal and business accounts, petitions, drafts of speeches, and resolutions, mainly concerning local politics and patronage, the Anti-Masonic Party, abolitionist agitation, temperance, the use of convict labor, pensions for veterans of the American Revolution and the War of 1812, opposition to the Bank of the United States, and land speculation in Michigan, Wisconsin, and other parts of the Midwest; also, correspondence and legal and financial papers pertaining to a case involving the Geneva & Rushville Plank Road Company (1849-50) and other lawsuits, to the settlement of the estates of the Brackett and James families, Orpha Gates, Oren Green, John Lee, Nathan Pratt, and Royal Stearns, and to Loomis's interest in Geneva College (1827-38), now Hobart College; also, a deed (1813) for land in the town of Gorham from Ann Ellice and her children; bills and tuition and board receipts (1832-34) from Genesee Wesleyan Seminary, Lima, Livingston County, New York, for Loomis's daughter, Amanda; thirty-three Civil War letters (162-64) written from various camps by his son, Charles, Morris O'Connell, Fayette Green, and other area men serving in the Union Army. Other correspondents include the Ontario County Antislavery Society, Skaneateles Antislavery Society, William Ansley, Samuel Colt, William T. Crittenden, Richard Gilbert, James Loomis, Congressman Meredith Mallory, and Augustus Torrey.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Merchant; postmaster, Rushville, New York; Associate Judge of Ontario County; New York State Senator, 1835-38.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include correspondence, deeds and agreements, personal and business accounts, petitions, drafts of speeches, and resolutions, mainly concerning local politics and patronage, the Anti-Masonic Party, abolitionist agitation, temperance, the use of convict labor, pensions for veterans of the American Revolution and the War of 1812, opposition to the Bank of the United States, and land speculation in Michigan, Wisconsin, and other parts of the Midwest; also, correspondence and legal and financial papers pertaining to a case involving the Geneva & Rushville Plank Road Company (1849-50) and other lawsuits, to the settlement of the estates of the Brackett and James families, Orpha Gates, Oren Green, John Lee, Nathan Pratt, and Royal Stearns, and to Loomis's interest in Geneva College (1827-38), now Hobart College; also, a deed (1813) for land in the town of Gorham from Ann Ellice and her children; bills and tuition and board receipts (1832-34) from Genesee Wesleyan Seminary, Lima, Livingston County, New York, for Loomis's daughter, Amanda; thirty-three Civil War letters (162-64) written from various camps by his son, Charles, Morris O'Connell, Fayette Green, and other area men serving in the Union Army. Other correspondents include the Ontario County Antislavery Society, Skaneateles Antislavery Society, William Ansley, Samuel Colt, William T. Crittenden, Richard Gilbert, James Loomis, Congressman Meredith Mallory, and Augustus Torrey.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Loomis, Chester,1789-1873.; Ansley, William.; Colt, Samuel, 1814-1862.; Crittenden, William T.; Gates, Orpha.; Gilbert, Richard.; Green, Fayette.; Green, Oren.; Lee, John.; Loomis, Amanda.; Loomis, Charles A.; Loomis, James.; Mallory, Meredith.; O'Connell, Morris.; Pratt, Nathan.; Stearns, Royal.; Torrey, Augustus.; Antimasonic Party.; Bank of the United States.; Genessee Wesleyan Seminary (Lima, N.Y.); Geneva and Rushville Plank Road Company.; Geneva College (N.Y.); Ontario County Antislavery Society.; Skaneateles Antislavery Society.
Subjects:
Freemasonry.; Postmasters.; Real property, Exchange of--Michigan.; Real property, Exchange of--Wisconsin.; Antislavery movements.; Temperance.; Veterans--United States.; Businessmen.; Judges.; Politicians.
Places:
New York (State)--Politics and government.; Ontario County (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Letters and papers regarding land and conditions in Wisconsin, Michigan, and the Midwest
Series II. Letters and papers regarding Oren Green
Series III. Letters and Papers regarding other estates
Series IV. Political papers and letters
Series V. Letters and papers regarding legal matters
Series VI. Letters and papers regarding claims for bounty and pension from veterans of War of 1812
Series VII. Letters and papers regarding Geneva and Rushville Plank Road Company lawsuit
Series VIII. Letters and papers regarding post office
Series IX. Letters and papers regarding education
Series X. Letters from and regarding William Ansley, Fairfax County, Virginia
Series XI. Letters and accounts of Samuel Colt, Geneva (Ontario County)
Series XII. Letters from Richard Gilbert regarding sale of pews in Rushville
Series XIII. Papers regarding Rushville
Series XIV. Miscellaneous
Series XV. Soldiers' Letters Civil War
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Letters and papers re land and conditions in Wisconsin, Michigan, and the Midwest
  - From Peleg Spencer, Danville, Illinois, May 16, 1830 (Box 1)
  - Letter inquiring re lands because writer had heard that Loomis had been "travelling in the Territory of Michigan for the purpose of viewing the country and purchasing land.", Mar. 1, 1831 (Box 1)
  - From St. Clair, Michigan, Jan. 23, 1832 (Box 1)
  - Tax bill, Genesee County, Michigan, 1840 (Box 4)
  - From Detroit re taxes, Sept. 23, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From C. Bellows, Oct. 8, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From Richard Gilbert (Wauwatosa, Wisconsin), 1842 (Box 4)
  - From James Loomis, Ypsilanti, Michigan, Dec. 5, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Mar. 23, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From F. M. Putney (New Berlin, Wisconsin), May 8, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Dec. 26, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From James Loomis, Jan. 1, 1844 (Box 4)
  - From W. Pitcher (White Pigeon, Michigan), Jan. 13, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Sept. 20, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From Heman Harwood (Constantine, Michigan), Feb. 8, 1845 (Box 5)
  - From James Loomis, June 30, 1845 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Nov. 25, 1845 (Box 5)
  - From Julius Steels (Constantine, St. Joseph's County, Michigan), Mar. 2, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Mar. 6, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Aug. 30, 1846 (Box 5)
  - Sale of Michigan land to Hiram Stowitz, Sept. 1, 1846 (Box 5)
  - W. W. Hodges, Sept. 5, 1846 (Box 5)
  - Account of Levi Sartwell Loomis, son of Eli she, Oct. 13, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From James Loomis, Nov. 19, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From Heman Harwood, Nov. 20, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From Rowland Perry (Grand Bank, Genesee County, Michigan), Dec. 10, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From F. M. Putney, Dec. 13, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From Berrien Spring, Michigan re taxes on Ox. E land, Feb. 24, 1847 (Box 5)
  - From R. B. Perry, June 8, 1847 (Box 5)
  - From Levi S. Loomis, June 24, 1847 (Box 5)
  - Account of Richard Gilbert, July 2, 1847 (Box 5)
  - From George F. Mead to Augustus Whitman and reply (Indiana), Dec. 1, 1847 (Box 5)
  - From Heman Harwood, Mar. 4, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Merrill Bates (Constantine, Michigan), June 20, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Heman Harwood, Sept. 5, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Norman Harvey (Constantine, Michigan), Sept. 25, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Milwaukee postmaster re draft sent, to Richard Gilbert, Nov. 14, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Nov. 27, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Berrien Spring, Michigan, Dec. 4, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Dec. 11, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From S. B. Mizner (Detroit), Apr. 3, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Hiram Stowitz (Grand Blanc), Apr. 7, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Copy of letter to 0. G. Nevins, June 2, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Oct. 5, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Hiram Stowitz, Oct. 8, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Madison, Wisconsin, Oct. 19, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Sherman Hinckley (Ypsilanti, Michigan), Dec. 12, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Feb. 21, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Madison, Wisconsin, Mar. 3, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert (Wisconsin), Mar. 13, 1850 (Box 6)
    "Some are mortgaging there [sic] farms and paying 25 & 30 percent for to get Money to go to California People are intoxicated an [sic] destracted [?] here in there [sic] imagination."
  - From James Loomis, Apr. 1, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Noah K. Green (Medina, Ohio), Apr. 15, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Heman Harwood, Apr. 27, 1850 (Box 6)
  - Bond of Hiram Stowitz to Loomis, July 20, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From John Howard Loomis (Wauwatosa, Wisconsin), Aug. 3, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Maria S. Loomis (Ypsilanti, Michigan), Oct. 4, 1850 (Box 6)
  - To M. Bartlett, Nov. 20, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Forest Harwood re Wisconsin land, Dec. 2, 1850 (Box 6)
  - Timothy Mower (Wauwatosa, Wisconsin), Dec. 25, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Charles A. Loomis (St. Clair, Michigan), Jan. 6, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Account re Michigan lands, Mar. 1, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Mar. 29, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From F. A. Harwood, Apr. 22, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Dec. 5, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From James Loomis, Mar. 14, 1853 (Box 6)
  - From R. W. Lendon (Niles, Michigan), June 30, 1853 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, July 2, 1853 (Box 6)
  - From Charles A. Loomis, Aug. 22, 1853 (Box 6)
  - From Charles A. Loomis, Mar. 21, 1857 (Box 7)
  - From E. G. Morgan re conditions near Fort Dodge, Iowa, Apr. 10, 1857 (Box 7)
  - From Charles A. Loomis, Mar. 17, 1853 (Box 6)
- Series II. Letters and papers regarding Oren Green
  - Account, 1820 (Box 1)
  - Settlement of Loomis and Green, Mar. 1, 1827 (Box 1)
  - Account, Feb. 7, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Mortgage to Green, Mar. 1, 1836 (Box 2)
  - Letter, May 11, 1839 (Box 4)
  - Account with Augustus Whitman, Feb. 24, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Morgage of Nathan Maynard for Wisconsin land, Apr. 1, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Account, Apr. 1841 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Rockford, Illinois, listing stock Green should bring to open a store in Milwauke, May 3, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Heman Harwood, May 12, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Copy of letter re mortgages in Warren County, Pennsylvania, May 28, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Copy of letter re_ mortgages in Warren Count Pennsylvania, June 14, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Rufus Harwood, June 27, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Heman Harwood, July 18, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Account of Richard Gilbert, Aug. 9, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From Silver Creek, New York, Sept. 18, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From Thomas Nevins re debt to Green, Sept. 20, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Bond dated Mar. 1, 1836, from James Watts, Oct. 4, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From Silver Creek, Oct. 12, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Account, Oct. 21, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Claim against estate by E. M. Gilbert (Utica), Oct. 22, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Rockford, Illinois, re Green's store (?) in Milwaukee, Nov. 16, 1841 (Box 4)
  - Account, Nov. 1841 (Box 4)
  - Account, Dec. 23, 1841 (Box 4)
  - From E. A. M. Gilbert, Jan. 17, 1842 (Box 4)
  - From Waldo Curtis re debt to Green, Mar. 22, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Loomis to Walter Hubbel1 and reply, Apr. 11, 1842 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, May 20, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Re property in Warren County, Pennsylvania, May 28, 1842 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, June 13, 1842 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, Aug. 11, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Account re mortgage of James Watts, Aug. 1842 (Box 4)
  - Settlement with William Crittenden, Oct. 13, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Walter Hubbel 1 re_ Auburn and Rochester RR stock, Nov. 1, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Re debt of John Hobart, Dec. 9, 1842 (Box 4)
  - Account re mortgage of James Watts, 1842 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, Jan. 9, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Account re RR stock, Feb. 13, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Walter Hubbel1, Apr. l0, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, May 11, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From W. W. Hodges re Pennsylvania land, May 30, 1843 (Box 4)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, Sept. 7, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Account, Oct. 4, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Copy of 1834 deed from Congdons and letter from W. W. Hodges, Oct. 25, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Re. debt of Green, Jan. 18, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From W. W. Hodges, Feb. 12, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From E, M. Gilbert, Feb. 20, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From E. M. Gilbert, June 11, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From W. W. Hodges, July 3, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From F. M. Putney re lands in Michigan, July 22, 1844 (Box 5)
  - Copy of letter to W. W. Hodges re sale of Pennsylvania land to Joseph Hall, July 30, 1844 (Box 5)
  - Bond and mortgage of Joseph Hall to Loomis, Walter Hubbel, and Sally Green, executors, Aug. 16, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From E. C. Pond re Wisconsin land, Oct. 26, 1844 (Box 5)
  - Account, Nov. 14, 1844 (Box 5)
  - From F. M. Putney, Feb. 2, 1845 (Box 5)
  - Accounts, Feb. 24, 1845 (Box 5)
  - From F. M. Putney, May 16, 1845 (Box 5)
  - From Chautauqua County Bank re land sold to Joseph Hall, Aug. 11, 1845 (Box 5)
  - Abstract of settlement, June 23, 1846 (Box 5)
  - From W. W. Hodges re land, Aug. 10, 1846 (Box 5)
  - Copy of letter to F. M. Putney, Sept. 2, 1847 (Box 5)
  - Letter from Richard Gilbert re land, Apr. 24, 1848 (Box 5)
  - Copy of letter to postmaster of Dunkirk (Dar County), Michigan, re sale of land, July 17, 1848 (Box 5)
  - Letter from Dunkirk postmaster, Aug. 5, 1848 (Box 5)
  - Settlement for rent of Samuel J. Hopkins, Oct. 9, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Dunkirk postmaster, Oct. 30, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From Dunkirk postmaster with extract of Loomis' reply, Jan. 15, 1849, Dec. 15, 1848 (Box 5)
  - From W. W. Hodges, Jan. 29, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Dunkirk postmaster; from Norman Harvey, Feb. 1, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Dunkirk postmaster, Mar. 13, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Letter re legacy of Green to American Home Missionary Society, June 23, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Sale by F. M. Putney of notes due the estate, June 25, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Copy of reply to June 23 letter, including appraisal and inventory, June 27, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Account of F. M. Putneyto Green estate, July 1, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Re land in Wisconsin, July 13, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Re land in Wisconsin; re. Watts mortgage, Sept. 22, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Auburn Theological Seminary re note of Green, Nov. 6, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Auburn Theological Seminary re note of Green, Nov. 14, 1849 (Box 5)
  - Re land in Michigan, Nov. 24, 1849 (Box 5)
  - From Noah Green, Apr. 20, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Apr. 26, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, May 2, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From W. W. Hodges, May 15, 1850 (Box 6)
  - Not Titled, May 21, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert; from W. W. Hodges, May 31, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, June 4, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From W. W. Hodges, Aug. 12, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Pittsfield, Michigan re. debt of Green, Aug. 19, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert, Nov. 25, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From W. W. Hodges, Nov. 26, 1850 (Box 6)
  - From Richard Gilbert; from Mrs. Betsey Green, Jan. 6, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Account, Jan. 29, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Agreement to see Wisconsin lot, Apr. 1, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From Mrs. C. Brackett, Apr. 3, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Notice of final settlement, Sept. 12, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From Noah Green, Oct. 10, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Account, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From Wm. S. Brigg, Jan. 5, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From A. Oliver, Feb. 4, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From N. B. Kidder, Feb. 5, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Assets and legacies remaining, Feb. 18, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From Noah Green, Feb. 20, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From A. Warren, Feb. 28, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From John L. Lewis, Jr., Mar. 16, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From Jason Downer, Mar. 18, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From Harriet F. Warren, Apr. 12, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Re Pennsylvania land, May 26, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Account, May 26, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Copy of answer to May 17 letter, June 1, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Receipts of legatees, June 23, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From Noah Green, July 10, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Copy of answer to July 10 letter, including account, Aug. 9, 1852 (Box 6)
  - From Albert S. Loomis re Pennsylvania and Wisconsin land, Oct. 25, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Re Pennsylvania land, Dec. 29, 1852 (Box 6)
  - Receipt from American Tract Society, Jan. 10, 1855 (Box 7)
  - Receipt from Noah Green, Jan. 23, 1855 (Box 7)
  - Receipt from American Home Missionary Society, Feb. 6, 1855 (Box 7)
  - Receipts from A.B.C.F. Missions, Mar. 15, 1855 (Box 7)
  - Receipt from American Education Society, Mar. 23, 1855 (Box 7)
- Series III. Letters and Papers regarding other estates
  - Joseph Chase, Apr. 22, 24, 1854 (Box 6)
  - Orpha Gates, Aug. 1860 - Sept. 1862 (Box 7)
  - Isaac Husted, Mar. 1828 - July 4, 1852 (Box 1-6)
  - William Lain, inventory, Jan. 8, 1839 (Box 4)
  - John Lee, January 25, 1858 - inventory, 1857 to 1858 (Box 7)
  - Daniel S, Morse, 1825 to 1849 (Box 5)
  - Nathan Pratt, Dec. 31, 1823 (Box 1)
  - Nathan Pratt, Feb. 28, 1825 (Box 1)
  - Royal Stearns, 1827 to 1849 (Box 5)
  - Abiel Thomas, 1852 to 1855 (Box 7)
  - Ebenezer Welch, 1839 to 1845 (Box 5)
- Series IV. Political papers and letters
  - Letter re election (of 1828?), Dec. 23, 1827 (Box 1)
  - Appointment of Loomis as judge of Ontario County Court, June 29, 1832 (Box 1)
  - From R[owland] Day in Washington re; U.S. Bank, Dec. 26, 1833 (Box 2)
  - Election returns, 3 printed pieces, Nov. 1834 (Box 2)
  - Draft of speech against U.S. Bank given at Jacksonville, Apr. 11, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Draft of speech against U.S. Bank given at Gorham, Apr. 1834 (Box 2)
  - Letter re liberal papers, June 1834 (Box 2)
  - Re impending elections, Sept. 26, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Reimpending elections, Oct. 18, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Draft of letter re use of convict labor, Oct. 28, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Letter re elections, Nov. 7, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Certificate of election, Nov. 29, 1834 (Box 2)
  - Re Hudson and Erie Canal, Mar. 5, 1835 (Box 2)
  - Printed report of Ontario County Republican Convention, Mar. 26, 1835 (Box 2)
  - Re banks, Jan. 20, 1836 (Box 2)
  - From H. Willson re nomination of Ontario County judges, Jan. 29, 1836 (Box 2)
  - Copy of letter of disapprobation to Emancipation and Human Riqhts, Feb. 11, 1836 (Box 2)
  - Draft of letter to Senator Leonard Maison, Apr. 22, 1836 (Box 2)
  - Extracts from and comments on New York Con­stitution, May 20, 1836 (Box 2)
  - From Augustus Torrey re appointment to (Yates?) County Court and note re "British outrage or frontier ", Jan. 5, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Copy of letter re Revolutionary War pension, Jan. 16, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Petition for appointment as notary public in Syracuse, Jan. 20, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Draft of letter re banking, Mar. 20, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Re election from H. Willson, Nov. 10, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Petition from Farmington Town Temperance Sac for support; letter from H. Willson, Nov. 13, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From W. B. Welles, Nov. 17, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From E. F. Miller, Nov. 24, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Re post office from Elisha F. Miller, Nov. 30, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Re post office from R. D. H. Yeckley, Dec. 4, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Re banking, Dec. 10, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From P. Tucker, Dec. 11, 1837 (Box 2)
  - Re banking, Dec. 16, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From E. Bradley, Dec. 19, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From E. F. Miller, Dec. 24, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From H. Willson, Dec. 28, 1837 (Box 2)
  - From H. Willson, Jan. 6, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Petition for appointment as notary public from Oliver Heartwell, Jan. 7, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From P. Tucker, Jan. 10, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From P. Tucker, Jan. 11, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re appointment of county court judges (Yates), Jan. 13, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From P. Tucker, Jan. 15, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Notes re banking bills, Jan. 18, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Letter re. banking bills; petition for appointment as postmaster in Palmyra, Jan. 19, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From B. J. Grosvenor, Jan. 20, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From E. F. Miller, Jan. 22, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From Torrey re appointment of judges, Jan. 24, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Petition against appointment of a third note public in Geneva, Jan. 25, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Copy of letter to A. H. Bennett, Jan. 27, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Notes on Whig speeches re Small Bill Law, Jan. 30, 1838 (Box 3)
  - M. Van Dusen letter re Small Bill Law sent to A1bany Argus, Jan. 31, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. H. Bennett; from H. Willson, Feb. 1, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Torrey, Feb. 5, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From R. H. Williams, Feb. 6, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Torrey, Feb. 7, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Petition for appointment to Indian Department; re county judges, Feb. 8, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re health officer for the Port of New York, Feb. 10, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From David Stout, Feb. 14, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Tarrey, Feb. 15, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re Yates County judges, Feb. 16, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From P. Tucker, Feb. 17, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re judges; copy of letter to New York Daily Advertiser re editorial about himself, Feb. 20, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From S. J. Bayard, Feb. 22, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re appointment of notary public in Syracuse, Feb. 23, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Torrey, Feb. 25, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From J. Willson, Feb. 26, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re Chemung (?) Canal, Feb. 28, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re naming the town of Bristol; re_ U. S. Bank, Mar. 2, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re nomination for commissioner of deeds in New York City, Mar. 3, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Torrey re Bank and currency, Mar. 4, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From R. M. Williams, Mar. 5, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re Yates County judges; from Harvey Hobart, Mar. 8, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From R. H. Williams; from G. J. Grosvenor, Mar. 1O, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From James Bogart, Mar. 12, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From R. H. Williams, Mar. 13, 1833 (Box 2)
  - Re Yates County judges; letter and petition re claims for land by Areh Campbell, Mar. 17, 1838 (Box 3)
  - -re Yates County judges, Mar. 20, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From shippers of flour re laws requiring inspection of flour before shipment from New York, Mar. 25, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Draft of bill to eliminate requirement that flour brought from other states be reinspected before shipment; re banking, Mar. 27, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re Yates County judges, Mar. 29, 1838 (Box 3)
  - US. Yates County judges, Mar. 31, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From Oliver Hartwel 1 to Governor Marcy re appointment as Commissioner of Deeds, Apr. 2, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Tarrey re banking; from Charles A. Loomis reporting election returns in Potter, Apr. 4, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From E. B. Jones re Penn Yan elections, Apr. 5, 1838 (Box 3)
  - OL Yates COunty judges, Apr. 6, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From R. D. H. Yeckley, Apr. 7, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re Oswego Canal, Apr. 9, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Copy of letter re Yates County judges, Apr. 10, 1838 (Box 3)
  - CJL Yates County judqes, Apr. 11, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From G. J. Grosvenor; from R. H, Williams, Apr. 12, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Re insurance company bill; from A. Torrey re bankinq, Apr. 13, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From J. Willson, Apri1 14, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From G. J. Grosvenor, Apr. 15, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From A. Lester, Apr. 16, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Printed statement and questions from Ontario, Sept. 29, 1838 (Box 3)
  - County Anti-Slavery Society
  - Draft of reply to Ontario County Anti-Slavery Society, Oct. 22, 1838 (Box 3)
  - Draft of letter to Skaneateles Anti-Slavery Society (he is opposed to slavery and to the annexation of Texas), Oct. 26, 1838 (Box 3)
  - From Michigan, Feb. 28, 1839 (Box 4)
  - From Meredith Mallory in Washington [then Representative from that district of Western New York. (26th Congress) K J D, Jan. 26, 1840 (Box 4)
  - Copy of letter attacking slavery, Apr. 14, 1840 (Box 4)
  - Petition and letter to Governor William L. Bouck re. appointment of Ephraim Blodget as Commissioner of Loans, Jan. 14, 1843 (Box 4)
  - Re election of Granger, Nov. 2, 1850 (Box 6)
  - Copy of remonstrance against agricultural college, Feb. 15, 1851 (Box 6)
  - From A. B. Coffin re. Democratic caucus, Mar. 25, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Re calling of county convention, Dec. 27, 1851 (Box 6)
  - Re town caucus, Jan. 1, 1852 (Box 6)